<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>industrial-automation on Vuong V. Trinh</title>
    <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/tags/industrial-automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in industrial-automation on Vuong V. Trinh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Vuong V. Trinh 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/tags/industrial-automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Resources for Automation and Control Professionals</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/technical-resources-for-automation-and-control-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/technical-resources-for-automation-and-control-professionals/</guid>
      <description>Automation &amp;amp; Control  A Guide to the Automation Body of Knowledge, Vernon L. Trevathan Instrument Engineers&amp;rsquo; Handbook: Process Measurement and Analysis, Béla G. Lipták Instrument Engineers&amp;rsquo; Handbook: Process Control and Optimization, Béla G. Lipták Instrument Engineers&amp;rsquo; Handbook: Process Software and Digital Networks, Béla G. Lipták The Condensed Handbook of Measurement and Control, N. E. Battikha Industrial Data Communications, Lawrence M. Thompson Basic and Advanced Regulatory Control: System Design and Application, Harold L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PID Control</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/pid-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/pid-control/</guid>
      <description>Anti-windup Techniques Incremental algorithm Back-calculation Conditional integration Parameters tuning First tuning Relay Method  Stable/Unstable processes No trajectory selection Need around 4 cycles: can take time for a slow process  Simple Internal Model Control Method (SIMC)  Stable process only Desired trajectory to be specified by user One single step: fast  Fine tuning Iterative Feedback Tuning Method (IFT)  Need an existing tuning not too bad Desired trajectory to be specified by user Close loop tuning: better safety Need around 4 cycles: can take time for a slow process Note: cannot be used if the set-point is calculated in PLC  References  Anti-Windup Techniques Automatic Tuning of Simple Regulators with Specifications on Phase and Amplitude Margins, Karl J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Advanced Control of Large Cryogenic Systems</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/cryogenic-refrigerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/cryogenic-refrigerator/</guid>
      <description>The ANR CRYOGREEN project gathers collaborative academic and industrial partners, including GIPSA-lab, CEA and CERN. We target to advanced control of large cryogenic systems via explicit nonlinear and hierarchical distributed model predictive control frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Management of Solar Thermodynamic Micro Power Plant</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/solar-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/solar-energy/</guid>
      <description>Fast nonlinear constrained control of a Stirling engine Process diagram 
Fast explicit constrained control synthesis 
Real-time validation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wood Pellet Production</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/wood-pellet-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/wood-pellet-production/</guid>
      <description> Drying Process Granulation &amp;amp; Pellet Mill </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>