<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Vuong V. Trinh</title>
    <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Vuong V. Trinh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Vuong V. Trinh 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Read data with multiple header rows into R</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/read-multiple-header-rows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/read-multiple-header-rows/</guid>
      <description>A shorter version of this blog post now appears as an article vignette for the readxl package, thank you to Jenny Bryan for the invitation!
 A problem I run up against a lot when working with other people’s data is having multiple header rows in the source data file. I like to use readr functions to read in rectangular data like .csv and .tsv files, but if you skip rows at import using the skip argument, you lose the header row as well, which usually has column names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies presentation ninja</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/r-ladies-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/r-ladies-slides/</guid>
      <description>So, you are doing an R-Ladies presentation…that’s awesome! The short version I made an R-Ladies theme for xaringan slides. My original tweet about it:
if you want to use @xieyihui&amp;#39;s awesome #xaringan package for #rstats slides but want more #Rladies flavor, there is now a built-in theme for that (with code highlighting)! Thanks to the awesome @RLadiesGlobal starter kit. Update the CSS in your YAML to use 🧙🏽‍♀️🧞‍♀️ pic.twitter.com/YnlGSVAMsl
&amp;mdash; Alison Hill (@apreshill) November 29, 2017  The way to use the theme is to update the YAML like so:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and running with blogdown</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/up-and-running-with-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/post/up-and-running-with-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>1 Read up on blogdown 2 Caveats, disclaimers, etc. 3 In GitHub 4 In terminal 5 In RStudio 6 Build your site in RStudio 7 Deploy in Netlify 8 Going further   1 Read up on blogdown Before you start, I recommend reading the following:
 blogdown: Creating Websites with R Markdown by Yihui Xie and Amber Thomas Making a Website Using blogdown, Hugo, and GitHub pages also by Amber Thomas  I also found this comment by Eric Nantz, the creator of the R-Podcast, in the rbind/support issues section on GitHub to be helpful:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>