<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>autism on Vuong V. Trinh</title>
    <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/tags/autism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in autism on Vuong V. Trinh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Vuong V. Trinh 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/tags/autism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Measurement of Language Outcomes for Neurodevelopmental Disorders - NIDCD R01</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/language-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/language-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Improving spoken language use (i.e., discourse skills) is a common treatment goal for children with neurodevelopmental disorders, particularly for those with difficulties in conversational reciprocity, perseverative speech, or idiosyncratic/stereotyped word use. These features are clinically meaningful, and in previous projects, we have successfully applied Natural Language Processing (NLP) methods to measure these discourse skills using natural language samples from children with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD). However, while NLP methods yield diagnostically relevant measures, it is not known if they can be translated into meaningful outcome measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-modal Autism Phenotype Snapshot (MAPS): Automated measurement of outcomes for children with autism</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/maps/</guid>
      <description>Targeting core symptoms of Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD) is a key treatment goal for parents of children with ASD. While many efficacious treatments for ASD have been developed, a major obstacle in evaluating these treatments among children with ASD has been the lack of adequate outcome measures (Anagnostou et al., 2014; Bolte &amp;amp; Diehl, 2013; Kanne et al., 2014). Most treatment studies have relied on informant-based measures (i.e., parent or clinician report) that either place a high burden on families, or require significant training and time to administer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Characterization of Language Use in Females and Males with Autism Spectrum Disorder</title>
      <link>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/sex-diffs-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vuongvtrinh.github.io/project/sex-diffs-language/</guid>
      <description>The female clinical presentation of Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) is not well understood, and is a contributing factor to underidentification and delays in the diagnosis of ASDs among females, particularly for those who are verbal and without cognitive impairments. Sex differences in clinical presentation may make it more difficult to recognize ASD symptoms in females, yet evidence for differences between females and males in the two core symptom domains—social communication/interaction and repetitive behaviors and restricted interests—has been inconsistent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>